This website uses cookies.   [Click here to learn more.](https://ecas.ec.europa.eu/cas/cookies.html;__Secure-ECAS_SESSIONID=Oau1-ODlT9go5U445R5DPCdEBEcC2AcyzBbbPBZzwsuj7mxSAmZCOFQEcknujOhk921!-1753075721 "Cookies")

Close this message

[EU Login](https://ecas.ec.europa.eu/cas/login;__Secure-ECAS_SESSIONID=Oau1-ODlT9go5U445R5DPCdEBEcC2AcyzBbbPBZzwsuj7mxSAmZCOFQEcknujOhk921!-1753075721)One account, many EU services[](https://ecas.ec.europa.eu/cas/;__Secure-ECAS_SESSIONID=Oau1-ODlT9go5U445R5DPCdEBEcC2AcyzBbbPBZzwsuj7mxSAmZCOFQEcknujOhk921!-1753075721# "Contrast")

български (bg) čeština (cs) dansk (da) Deutsch (de) eesti (et) ελληνικά (el) English (en) español (es) français (fr) Gaeilge (ga) hrvatski (hr) italiano (it) latviešu (lv) lietuvių (lt) magyar (hu) Malti (mt) Nederlands (nl) polski (pl) português (pt) română (ro) slovenčina (sk) slovenščina (sl) suomi (fi) svenska (sv)

Privacy Statement
-----------------

Privacy statement for users registered with the European Commission's Identity and Access Management Service (IAMS)  
(DPR-EC-03187)

### 1\. INTRODUCTION

The European Commission (hereafter 'the Commission') is committed to protect your personal data and to respect your privacy. The Commission collects and further processes personal data pursuant to [Regulation (EU) 2018/1725](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2018.295.01.0039.01.ENG&toc=OJ:L:2018:295:TOC) of the European Parliament and of the Council of 23 October 2018 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data by the Union institutions, bodies, offices and agencies and on the free movement of such data (repealing Regulation (EC) No 45/2001).

This privacy statement explains the reason for the processing of your personal data, the way we collect, handle and ensure protection of all personal data provided, how that information is used and what rights you have in relation to your personal data. It also specifies the contact details of the responsible Data Controller with whom you may exercise your rights, the Data Protection Officer and the European Data Protection Supervisor.

The information in relation to processing operation 'EU Login', undertaken by EC DIGIT B3, is presented below.

### 2\. WHY AND HOW DO WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

Purpose of the processing operation:  
EU Login is the European Commission's central authentication service.  
It acts as an authentication service that verifies the identity of the user and it allows users to access a wide range of European Commission resources including websites, applications and services, by using a single account.  
Identity and Access Management Service (IAMS - DPR-EC-08606) provides EU Login with the necessary information to create EU Login accounts.  
EU Login can be used by any individual either at its own initiative (by either creating a self-registered account, using an existing account on one of the following social media platforms: Meta/Facebook, X/Twitter, Google, or using its own eID) or at the initiative of the organization they represent, by automatic transfer of information from the user's organization to the European Commission. In all of these cases, EU Login will create a user account.

EU Login also adds a layer of protection to the sign-in process, through the multifactor authentication (2FA or MFA). It provides the following easy to use verification methods:

**For EU Institutions staff:**

* simple user password
* OTP (one Time Password) sent as SMS to the user's mobile (GSM) number registered in the personal EU Login profile
* EU Login Mobile Application (PIN code, or any alternate capabilities offered by the owned mobile device)
* Physical Security Tokens (Security Keys)
* Trusted Platforms
* Physical Security Tokens (OTP enabled) provided by the organization

**For self-registered individuals (including identity federation with eID and social media accounts):**

* simple user password
* OTP (One Time Password)sent as SMS to the user's mobile (GSM) number registered in the personal EU Login profile
* EU Login Mobile Application (PIN code, or any alternate capabilities offered by the owned mobile device)
* Physical Security Tokens (Security Keys)
* Trusted Platforms

Your personal data will not be used for an automated decision-making, including profiling.

Individual Commission (and other EU Institutions) sites and applications that use EU Login for authenticating users, may nevertheless collect additional personal data themselves. This data processing will be covered by the relevant sites' own privacy statements.

### 3\. ON WHAT LEGAL GROUND(S) DO WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We process your personal data, because:

(a) Processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Union institution or body;

The processing is necessary for the performance and support of tasks carried out by the institution as mandated by the Treaties, in particular Articles 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 11, 17, of the Treaty of the European Union and Articles 2, 4, 67, 310, 325 of the Treaty of the Functioning of the European Union.

Commission Decision (EU, Euratom) 2017/46 of 10 January 2017 on the security of communication and information systems in the European Commission and Information Security Policy and Internal Rules for handling ICT Information Security Incidents, the Commission Information Systems Security Policy C(2006)3602.

Regulation No 31 (EEC), 11 (EAEC), laying down the Staff Regulations of Officials and the Conditions of Employment of Other Servants of the European Economic Community and the European Atomic Energy Community (OJ 45, 14.6.1962, p. 1385), as last amended by Commission Delegated Regulation (EU) 2016/1611 of 7 July 2016.

This processing operation is also in line with Regulation (EU) 2018/1724 on establishing a single digital gateway to provide access to information, to procedures and to assistance and problem-solving services and amending Regulation (EU) No 1024/2012 and within the scope of the EC's eGovernment Action Plan 2016-2020 on accelerating the digital transformation of governments.

The above-mentioned legal basis applies to the EU-login users that have an employment relationship with the EU Institutions, agencies and Bodies (EU Staff).

The personal data of the self-registered individuals is processed based on their consent after having read, understood and agreed to this privacy statement. Consent can be withdrawn at any time. The withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

### 4\. WHICH PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT AND FURTHER PROCESS?

In order to carry out this processing operation EC DIGIT B3 collects the following categories of personal data:

**For EU Institutions staff**

* Personal information:
    * First and last name(s) as provided by the HR Systems
    * personal title
    * a unique number per EU Institution, Agency or Body attributed by the HR System of each entity (Personal Number)
    * a corporate email address (replaced by a personal one in the case of post activity staff like retirees, unemployed)Based on the above, IAMS generates an account.
* EU Login keeps as well:
    * information used for multifactor authentication
    * mobile phone number (for two-factor authentication, when available into the HR System)
    * type and model of the mobile device (in case of using EU Login Mobile Application)
    * a history of activity logs performed by each account, for security purposes.This additional information is used to diagnose and resolve problems and to deal with security incidents as well as to avoid duplicated accounts. This information can help in following up any doubtful/malicious activity relating to the user account.
* Administrative data (to identify the relationship with the organization):
    * the entity where the individual is assigned
    * account status
    * organization allocated office phone number
    * mobile phone number (for two-factor authentication, when available into the HR System)

**For self-registered individuals**

* Personal information (as provided by the individual during self-registration):
    * first, middle and last name(s)
    * email address
    * username
    * mobile number, when provided for two-factor authentication
    * from Social Media Platforms, EU Login receives only, the e-mail address and the name(s)/surname or the identifier known by the Social Media Platform
    * eID identifier (in case of using eID for authentication)

EU Login keeps as well the type, model and operating system software of the mobile device, for the two-factor authentication, while using the EU Login mobile app.

Note that EU Login does not receive any data (including any personal data) captured by the cookies of the Social Media Platform.

**Please note that if you choose the option to use Social Media Platforms to authenticate to EU Login, the European Commission strongly recommends that you read the privacy statements/notices of the related social platforms, since they are also applicable.**

**Log files for both user categories**

Each time the user logs to EU Login, a history of the account activity will be recorded in the logs, for security purposes.

Note that, for cyber security and system monitoring purposes of this processing activity, logs are collected in the European Commission Logs Correlation Service (cf. DPR-EC-2986).

We have obtained your personal data either from the IAMS (DPR-EC-08606) for the EU Institutions staff or directly from the data subject for the self-registered individuals and from Sign-In services via the federation with Social Media platforms and eID.

### 5\. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

EC DIGIT B3 only keeps your personal data for the time necessary to fulfil the purpose of collection.

Data related to the European Institutions Staff are kept for as long as the user has an active assignment in one of the European Institutions, Agencies and Bodies and, the personal data is made available to the IAMS.

Data related to self-registered individuals is kept until the user personally deletes his/her EU-Login account, or requests the deletion by our Unit.

Log files are kept for 6 months.

### 6\. HOW DO WE PROTECT AND SAFEGUARD YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

All personal data in electronic format (databases) are stored on the servers of the European Commission. All processing operations are carried out pursuant to the [Commission Decision (EU, Euratom) 2017/46](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1548093747090&uri=CELEX:32017D0046) of 10 January 2017 on the security of communication and information systems in the European Commission.

In order to protect your personal data, the Commission has put in place a number of technical and organisational measures. Technical measures include appropriate actions to address online security, risk of data loss, alteration of data or unauthorised access, taking into consideration the risk presented by the processing and the nature of the personal data being processed. Organisational measures include restricting access to the personal data solely to authorised persons with a legitimate need to know for the purposes of this processing operation.

### 7\. WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND TO WHOM IS IT DISCLOSED?

Access to your personal data is provided to the Commission staff responsible for carrying out this processing operation and to authorised staff according to the "need to know" principle. Such staff abide by statutory, and when required, additional confidentiality agreements.

Personal data is not shared with other recipients, or transferred to third countries or international organisations.

The information we collect will not be given to any third party, except to the extent and for the purpose we may be required to do so by law.

### 8\. WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS AND HOW CAN YOU EXERCISE THEM?

You have specific rights as a "data subject" under Chapter III (Articles 14-25) of Regulation (EU) 2018/1725, in particular the right to access, your personal data and to rectify them in case your personal data are inaccurate or incomplete. Where applicable, you have the right to erase your personal data, to restrict the processing of your personal data, to object to the processing, and the right to data portability.  
You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data, which is lawfully carried out pursuant to Article 5(1)(a) on grounds relating to your particular situation.

For self-registered individuals:  
You have consented to provide your personal data to EC DIGIT B3 for the present processing operation. You can withdraw your consent at any time by notifying the Data Controller. You may also delete your account at any time. The withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of the processing carried out before you have withdrawn the consent.

You can exercise your rights by contacting the Data Controller, or in case of conflict the Data Protection Officer. If necessary, you can also address the European Data Protection Supervisor. Their contact information is given under Heading 9 below.

Where you wish to exercise your rights in the context of one or several specific processing operations, please provide their description (i.e. their Record reference(s) as specified under Heading 10 below) in your request.

### 9\. CONTACT INFORMATION

**The Data Controller**  
If you would like to exercise your rights under Regulation (EU) 2018/1725, or if you have comments, questions or concerns, or if you would like to submit a complaint regarding the collection and use of your personal data, please feel free to contact:

* For EU Institutions staff, your HR department; then all modifications will be automatically reflected in EU Login;
* For self-registered individuals, directly the Data Controller, at: [EU-LOGIN-EXTERNAL-SUPPORT@ec.europa.eu.](mailto:EU-LOGIN-EXTERNAL-SUPPORT@ec.europa.eu)

**The Data Protection Officer (DPO) of the Commission**  
You may contact the Data Protection Officer [(DATA-PROTECTION-OFFICER@ec.europa.eu)](mailto:DATA-PROTECTION-OFFICER@ec.europa.eu) with regard to issues related to the processing of your personal data under Regulation (EU) 2018/1725.

**The European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS)**  
You have the right to have recourse (i.e. you can lodge a complaint) to the European Data Protection Supervisor [(edps@edps.europa.eu)](mailto:edps@edps.europa.eu) if you consider that your rights under Regulation (EU) 2018/1725 have been infringed as a result of the processing of your personal data by the Data Controller.

### 10\. WHERE TO FIND MORE DETAILED INFORMATION

The Commission Data Protection Officer (DPO) publishes the register of all processing operations on personal data by the Commission, which have been documented and notified to him. You may access the register via the following link: [http://ec.europa.eu/dpo-register](http://ec.europa.eu/dpo-register).

This specific processing operation has been included in the DPO's public register with the following Record reference: DPR-EC-03187

* [Help](https://trusted-digital-identity.europa.eu/eu-login-help_en;__Secure-ECAS_SESSIONID=Oau1-ODlT9go5U445R5DPCdEBEcC2AcyzBbbPBZzwsuj7mxSAmZCOFQEcknujOhk921!-1753075721 "Help") (opens in a new tab)
* [My Account](https://ecas.ec.europa.eu/cas/userdata/myAccount.cgi;__Secure-ECAS_SESSIONID=Oau1-ODlT9go5U445R5DPCdEBEcC2AcyzBbbPBZzwsuj7mxSAmZCOFQEcknujOhk921!-1753075721 "My Account") (opens in a new tab)

* [European Union](https://europa.eu;__secure-ecas_sessionid=oau1-odlt9go5u445r5dpcdebecc2acyzbbbpbzzwsuj7mxsamzcofqecknujohk921!-1753075721/ "European Union")(opens in a new tab)
* [EU institutions](https://europa.eu/about-eu/institutions-bodies/index_en.htm;__Secure-ECAS_SESSIONID=Oau1-ODlT9go5U445R5DPCdEBEcC2AcyzBbbPBZzwsuj7mxSAmZCOFQEcknujOhk921!-1753075721 "EU institutions")(opens in a new tab)

9.11.1-dn1p | 2 ms

Powered by[](https://europa.eu;__secure-ecas_sessionid=oau1-odlt9go5u445r5dpcdebecc2acyzbbbpbzzwsuj7mxsamzcofqecknujohk921!-1753075721/)
